Marcus Chiu

Full Stack Developer

www.marcuschiu.com linkedin.com/in/marcusrchiu marcuschiu9@gmai.com 469-422-1059

FOCUS

- Web Services
- Computer Networks
- Algorithm Design & Analysis
- Pattern Recognition

WEBSITES

www.marcuschiu.com

Documentation

- confluence.marcuschiu.com *
- doc.marcuschiu.com
- wiki.marcuschiu.com

Proof of Concept

- chat.marcuschiu.com

TECH STACK

Main Languages

- Java
- Typescript & Web Languages
- MySQL
- Python
- Shell

Frameworks

- SpringBoot
- Angular6
- TensorFlow

Web Services

- Amazon Web Services
- Web APIs (REST, GraphQL, WebSockets, WebRTC, etc)

Other

- Linux (Debian/RPM)

OTHER INTERESTS

- Finger-Style Guitar
- Human Science
- History, Philosophy, Religion

OBJECTIVE

Master's student studying Intelligent Systems with an expected graduation date of May 2020. Results-oriented professional with several years experience as a Software Developer and DevOps Engineer. Love building web services, computer networks and implementing algorithms. Interested in growing my skill set and applying it to challenging problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer — Kibo Commerce

November 2017 - March 2018

managing multiple auto-deployments within the AWS infrastructure while utilizing Jenkins - Chef - CloudFormation

Software Engineer — Kibo Commerce

September 2016 - November 2017

maintaining a large and complex order management system with multiple client specific requirements and expectations

Android Developer — Ghoomo

January 2016 - May 2016

providing overall leadership to the entire project team and disseminating tasks in an effective manner Android Studio - Java - MySQL - PHP - Yelp API

EDUCATION

MS in CS — University of Texas at Dallas

August 2018 - Expected May 2020

intelligent systems & computer networks

BS in CS — University of Texas at Dallas

August 2012 - May 2016

explored a wide range of topics: android apps, web development, r&d computer vision and graphics, AI, computer architecture, and software design patterns

PROJECTS

Doc Web App — doc.marcuschiu.com

Version 1 - March 2018 - May 2018

a web application encompassing devops, backend, and frontend SpringBoot - Nginx - Angular5 - RaspberryPi - AWS - Proxy -MongoDB